Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Philosophy, Honors Theses SC4-4434
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of Philosophy, honors theses
1985-2009
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Department of Philosophy
SC4-4434
1.25 Linear Feet 23 volumes (3 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduates in the Stanford University Dept. of Philosophy.
Acquisition Information
Theses were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Access to Collection
The collection is open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduates in the Stanford University Dept. of Philosophy.
Student papers.; Philosophy -- Study and teaching.; Stanford University. Department of Philosophy
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Eisenstein, Jacob, Computers, creativity, Kuhn: philosophy of science and the artistic machine., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Hammour, Mohamad, Wittgenstein on necessity and grammar., 1985 (Box 1)
  - Kaufmann,Kathleen, Do racial preferences promote racial justice? An analysis inspired by the University of Michigan and Gratz vs. Bollinger., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Martinez, Sierra, Relationships and persons., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Meadows, Katie, The psychology of the Pyrrhonian skeptic., 2009 (Box 1)
  - Mehta, Anuragh, Recentering the incompatibilist/compatibilist debate on free will., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Primus, Kristin, Metaphor, 'What is said,' and the cultivation of intimacies., 2004 (Box 1)
  - Shen, Andrew, From a moral foundation: a new approach to the problem of personal identity., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Waddell, Laura, The multiple incapacitation theory of mental illness., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Yegnashankaran, Kritika, Attempting to undermine the gene's central role in evolution: does developmental systems theory succeed?., 1998 (Box 1)
  - McCornick, Kirstie, Kant on the morality of living., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Jenkins, Scott, Wittgenstein on meaning and the mind., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Robb, David M., Mental images and pictures: an inquiry into representational format., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Napili, Angela, Action in Charles Peirce's philosophy of mathematics., 1994 (Box 2)
  - Nauckhoff, Josefine, Kant's free play of the faculties in aesthetic experience: key to a universal ethic?., 1987 (Box 2)
  - Cope, Eric, Metaphysics, Nihilism, and difference: Heidegger and Nietzsche., 1994 (Box 2)
  - Lombrozo, Tania, Teleology and optimality in adaptive explanations of cognition., 2002 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Victoria, Can past deprivation excuse present depravity?., 2004 (Box 2)
  - Beim, Nicholas, Akrasia and compunction., 1993 (Box 2)
  - Ross, Robert Waters, Is it alive? A critique of the strong artificial life claim., 1995 (Box 2)
  - Kleha, Stephen, Humanity, distributive justice and international morality., 1999 (Box 2)
  - Kurlekar, Amit, Rational pluralism: a moderate alternative to monist and relativist outlooks on moral experience., 1998 (Box 2)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2018-060
  - Cristy, Rachel, "The evolution of W.E.B. DuBois's philosophy of race", 2011 Mar 11 (Box 1)
  - Lichtenstein, Eli, "Cognitive values and the problems of theory choice", 2011 May 13 (Box 1)